Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got an upper intermediate level lesson for you all
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节中高级课程。
about money.
关于金钱。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to talk about the stock market.
我们将讨论股票市场。
So a very interesting topic, very current as well because well throughout the world
这是一个非常有趣的话题，也非常贴近时事，因为全球范围内
stock markets are not doing very well.
股票市场表现不佳。
That's right and you may have seen on the television a lot of information about this.
没错，你可能在电视上看到过很多相关信息。
So today we're going to hopefully explain some of the things and phrases and words that
所以今天，我们希望解释一些你一直听到的
you've been hearing.
术语和短语。
But first we've got a couple of important indicators, a couple of acronyms actually
但首先，我们有几个重要的指标，实际上是一些缩写词，
that you're going to hear about.
你将会听到它们。
So let's look at those in today's vocabulary preview.
那么，让我们看看今天词汇预览中的内容。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So the first word that we have on vocabulary preview is the NASDAQ.
词汇预览中的第一个词是纳斯达克。
NASDAQ.
纳斯达克。
N-A-S-D-A-Q.
N-A-S-D-A-Q。
So this is basically the American stock market.
所以这基本上就是美国股市。
Right.
对。
It's an acronym.
它是一个缩写。
Now it's a really, really long acronym so we're not going to get into it but it is basically
现在它是一个非常非常长的缩写，所以我们不打算深入解释，但它基本上就是
the American stock market where all these companies are trading stock, publicly traded
美国股市，所有那些公司都在这里交易股票，公开交易的
companies.
公司。
Right.
对。
So publicly traded companies, you're basically trading their stocks through NASDAQ.
所以公开交易的公司，你基本上是通过纳斯达克交易它们的股票。
Right.
对。
And now the next one that we have is an indicator which tells us how well some companies or
现在我们下一个要讲的是一个指标，它告诉我们一些公司或
some stock are doing and that's the Dow Jones indicator.
一些股票表现如何，那就是道琼斯指标。
Dow Jones indicator.
道琼斯指标。
So maybe if the Dow Jones is really low for something, we think, man, it's not doing so
所以如果道琼斯指数对某件事来说非常低，我们就会想，天哪，它表现不太好。
well.
不太好。
Right.
对。
If it goes up, things are improving.
如果它上涨，情况就在改善。
Right.
对。
So usually the Dow Jones has the, it's based upon the 50 biggest companies in the United
所以通常道琼斯指数是基于美国最大的50家公司，
States, the 50 biggest publicly traded companies.
最大的50家公开交易公司。
Now you can divide it into like industrial companies or pharmaceutical companies, etc.
现在你可以把它分成工业公司或制药公司等等。
But in general, that's the indicator and how it works.
但总的来说，这就是指标及其运作方式。
Great.
太好了。
So we're going to listen to today's dialogue and find out how these words are used in context
所以我们将听今天的对话，看看这些词在语境中如何使用。
and we're back in a moment to talk about what's going on.
我们稍后回来讨论发生了什么。
Sorry to bother you, sir, but I have some bad news.
抱歉打扰您，先生，但我有个坏消息。
What is it?
什么事？
Well, the stock market just took a huge plunge and we've lost a lot of money.
嗯，股市刚刚暴跌，我们损失了很多钱。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
What happened?
发生了什么？
There are many factors that weigh in, but NASDAQ is down 200 points.
有很多因素影响，但纳斯达克指数下跌了200点。
The Dow Jones indicator also suffered.
道琼斯指数也受到了影响。
Our portfolio is worth half of what it was worth one week ago.
我们的投资组合价值只有一周前的一半。
How is this possible?
这怎么可能？
You are supposed to be talking to our stockbrokers and making sure that our securities and investments
你应该在跟我们的股票经纪人沟通，确保我们的证券和投资
are safe and making a profitable return.
安全且能获得盈利回报。
I know, sir.
我知道，先生。
We didn't expect a bull market to become a bear market all of a sudden.
我们没预料到牛市会突然变成熊市。
On the other hand, you still have some high yield trash bonds and government bonds that
另一方面，你还有一些高收益垃圾债券和政府债券，
will give us enough liquidity to cut our losses and reinvest in emerging markets.
它们能给我们足够的流动性来止损，并重新投资于新兴市场。
We could potentially make this tragedy work for us and make us think outside the box.
我们有可能把这场悲剧变成机会，让我们跳出固有思维。
Do what you have to do.
做你该做的事。
One other thing.
还有一件事。
Don't tell the rest of the stockholders about this.
别告诉其他股东这件事。
If they find out it's the end of this company.
如果他们发现了，公司就完了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a lot of interesting words there.
这里有很多有趣的词。
I think a lot of them were very specific to the stock market and very, maybe a little
我觉得其中很多词非常针对股市，可能有点
bit difficult.
难懂。
Why don't we take a look at a couple of those and language takeaway.
我们不如看看其中几个词，进入语言学习环节。
Language takeaway.
语言学习环节。
Okay, so this first word is a very important word in banking and finance.
好的，第一个词在银行和金融领域非常重要。
We talk about portfolios a lot.
我们经常谈论投资组合。
So portfolio.
投资组合。
Right.
对。
So basically a portfolio is the variety of things that you own.
基本上，投资组合就是你拥有的各种资产。
For example, in the stock market, it could be stocks, it could be bonds, it can be mutual
比如在股市中，可以是股票、债券、共同
funds, etc.
基金等等。
Or for example, if you're a company, your product portfolio could be all the products
或者，如果你是一家公司，你的产品组合就是公司拥有的所有产品。
that your company owns.
没错。
That's right.
对。
So in this case, our portfolio is worth half what it was a week ago.
所以在这种情况下，我们的投资组合价值只有一周前的一半。
And so this is a sentence that means, we've lost half of the money we invested.
这句话的意思是，我们损失了一半的投资资金。
All of our investments are in a portfolio.
我们所有的投资都在一个投资组合里。
We talk about them as a portfolio.
我们把这些投资统称为一个投资组合。
And when we lose money, we say our portfolio is worth less now than it was before.
当我们亏钱时，我们会说投资组合现在比以前价值更低了。
Exactly.
没错。
So moving on, he starts to talk about the bull market and the bear market.
接着往下，他开始谈论牛市和熊市。
So what is this all about?
这到底是怎么回事？
Well, a bull is an animal with horns.
嗯，公牛是一种有角的动物。
And a bear is another animal.
而熊是另一种动物。
So we're not talking about animals here.
但我们这里不是在讨论动物。
We're talking about special finance phrases.
我们在讨论特殊的金融术语。
So the bull market would be, again, talking about companies and trading.
所以牛市，再次强调，是关于公司和交易的。
It would be maybe a market that's growing very rapidly.
它可能是一个增长非常迅速的市场。
That's very, very strong.
非常非常强劲。
That's a bull market.
那就是牛市。
So people often talk about China's bull market, right?
所以人们经常谈论中国的牛市，对吧？
How China continues to grow and grow and grow and grow.
中国如何持续增长、增长、再增长。
But a market that slows down, like the United States last year, would be a bear market.
但一个放缓的市场，比如去年的美国，就是熊市。
Right.
对。
So think of a bear, maybe it's sleeping, it goes into hibernation.
所以想象一只熊，也许它在睡觉，进入冬眠状态。
That's a bear market.
那就是熊市。
So a slow market.
所以是一个缓慢的市场。
It's not really growing.
它并没有真正增长。
Very good.
非常好。
But talking about a portfolio again, we might have stocks.
但再说到投资组合，我们可能有股票。
But in this case, the two people are talking about their bonds.
但在这个例子里，这两个人在谈论他们的债券。
So he says, you still have some high yield trash bonds and government bonds.
所以他说，你还有一些高收益垃圾债券和政府债券。
What's a high yield bond and what's a trash bond?
什么是高收益债券和垃圾债券？
Okay.
好的。
So when we think about the word yield is how much it gives, right?
当我们想到“收益”这个词时，它指的是能带来多少回报，对吧？
So how much we are getting from it.
也就是我们能从中得到多少。
So something that is high yield means that you're getting a lot from it.
所以高收益意味着你能从中获得很多。
For example, this orange tree yields 300 oranges per year.
比如，这棵橙树每年产出300个橙子。
Okay.
好的。
So how much we get from it.
所以我们从中得到多少。
Exactly.
没错。
So we're getting 300 oranges.
所以我们得到300个橙子。
That's how much it's yielding.
这就是它的产出量。
And so basically that's what yield means.
所以基本上这就是“收益”的意思。
So when we talk about trash bonds, this on the other hand, it's a word that's maybe a
那么当我们谈论垃圾债券时，另一方面，这个词可能有点棘手，但债券是卖家给你的承诺，他会连本带利还你钱。
little bit tricky, but a bond is a promise that you get from the seller that he's going
但垃圾债券是一种风险很高的债券。
to pay you back the money that you give him with interest.
这意味着卖家可能不会还你钱，因为他还在努力筹集资金。
But a trash bond is a very risky bond.
对，但高收益垃圾债券意味着你可能从这种债券中赚很多钱，当然除非它不太可靠。
It means that the seller might not pay you back because he's still trying to get all
没错。
the money.
所以它有风险。
Right, but a high yield trash bond means that you might make a lot of money from this bond
当然，因为风险更高，所以收益也更高。
unless of course it's not very dependable.
很好。
Exactly.
所以是高收益垃圾债券。
So it's risky.
那这个呢？
Of course, since it's riskier, it has more yield.
它们会给我们流动性来减少损失。
Great.
流动性。
So high yields trash bond.
我们在金融领域经常听到流动性这个词。
And then what about this?
没错。
They will give us liquidity to cut our losses.
也许在你的公司里，会计会提到这个。
Liquidity.
基本上就是手头有现金。
We hear all about liquidity in finance.
这样你就有钱支付或购买东西。
Exactly.
不是用...
Maybe in your company, the accountant will talk about this.
所以它是可用的。
And that's basically just to have money cash in hand.
可用的，是的。
So you have money to pay things or to buy things.
不是用信贷。
Not with...
与信贷相反。
So it's available.
好的，流动性。
Available, yeah.
最后，相反地，我们该怎么办？
Not with credit.
让我们跳出固有思维。
The opposite of credit.
我们可以再投资于新兴市场。
Okay, liquidity.
最近这是一个很热门的话题，关于新兴市场。
And finally, instead, what are we going to do?
所以“emerge”意思是出现、上升。
Let's think outside the box.
是的，出来。
We could reinvest in emerging markets.
所以它几乎像是新的或增长中的市场。
And this is a very hot topic lately, talking about emerging markets.
所以在这种情况下，一个市场，比如新兴市场，可能是东南亚市场，它增长很快，或者你甚至可以说西非市场。
So to emerge means to come up, to rise.
我们谈论的是世界上尚未成熟的地方。
Yeah, to come out.
它们不是老牌且可靠的。
So it's almost like new or growing markets.
它们是新的且令人兴奋的。
So in this case, a market, an emerging market would be, for example, the Southeast Asian
对。
market, which is growing quickly, or even you could say West African market.
没错。
We're talking about places in the world that aren't established.
所以它有风险。
They're not old and dependable.
当然，因为风险更高，所以收益也更高。
They're new and exciting.
很好。
Right.
所以是高收益垃圾债券。
So they're coming up.
所以他们正在崛起。
So that's an emerging market.
所以那是一个新兴市场。
So a lot of very interesting words and phrases.
所以有很多非常有趣的单词和短语。
They're very related to our topic.
它们与我们的主题非常相关。
And so why don't we move on now.
那么，我们为什么不继续往下呢。
Let's take a look at two key phrases on Fluency Builder.
让我们看看“流利度构建器”中的两个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
This first phrase is something we've heard a lot about in the last year or two with things
第一个短语是我们在过去一两年里经常听到的，因为
not going so well in the world of finance.
金融领域的情况不太顺利。
The first one, here we go, to cut our losses.
第一个，来了，止损。
Okay, so let's cut our losses.
好的，那我们就止损吧。
So when you talk about cutting your losses, that means to try and stop losing money somehow,
所以当你谈论止损时，意思是试图以某种方式停止亏损，
maybe sell early.
也许早点卖出。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case, we're losing money.
所以在这种情况下，我们正在亏损。
Let's stop now.
我们现在就停下来。
Let's stop everything.
停止一切。
Cut our losses.
止损。
That means cut them away.
意思是把它们切掉。
Forget about them.
忘掉它们。
Throw them away and start again.
扔掉它们，重新开始。
Okay, so we could say, my business is failing.
好的，所以我们可以说，我的生意失败了。
I'm going to cut my losses, sell the business and start again.
我要止损，卖掉生意，重新开始。
Right.
对。
That's exactly it.
就是这样。
So to cut your losses means to stop doing something, maybe sell it and stop losing money.
所以止损意味着停止做某事，也许卖掉它，停止亏损。
Basically, you accept the fact that you lost it.
基本上，你接受自己已经亏损的事实。
You can't get it back and start again.
你无法挽回，然后重新开始。
So when they were talking about investing in emerging markets, he said, well, maybe
所以当他们谈论投资新兴市场时，他说，嗯，也许
we could do this and that would force us to think outside the box.
我们可以这样做，那会迫使我们跳出框框思考。
Okay, this is a great phrase and you might hear this in meetings a lot or from your manager.
好的，这是一个很棒的短语，你可能在会议中或从经理那里经常听到。
What's going on here is these two people are talking about how they lost a lot of money.
这里的情况是，这两个人在谈论他们如何亏损了很多钱。
The economy is bad and they've been doing things in a normal way for a long time.
经济不好，他们长期以来一直按常规方式做事。
It's not working.
但行不通。
Let's think outside the box.
让我们跳出框框思考。
That means let's be creative.
意思是让我们有创意。
Let's try and discover new ways of doing things that will yield positive results.
让我们尝试发现新的做事方式，从而产生积极的结果。
That's right.
没错。
This is a very, very common phrase, very widely used in business or when you're talking about
这是一个非常非常常见的短语，在商业或谈论
ideas is people tell you to think outside the box to maybe break some of the rules.
想法时广泛使用，人们会告诉你跳出框框思考，也许打破一些规则。
Right, right.
对，对。
Don't just think the way that you always do.
不要总是按你习惯的方式思考。
Don't do the same thing over and over.
不要一遍又一遍地做同样的事。
Do something new, be creative, come up with something great.
做点新的事情，要有创意，想出一些很棒的点子。
So that's thinking outside the box.
所以那就是跳出框框思考。
Right, very good.
对，非常好。
So a lot of great phrases there.
所以那里有很多很棒的短语。
I think we've learned quite a bit.
我想我们学到了不少。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue one last time and we'll be back to talk a little bit
我们为什么不最后再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一聊
more about this very interesting topic.
这个非常有趣的话题。
Sorry to bother you, sir, but I have some bad news.
抱歉打扰您，先生，但我有一些坏消息。
What is it?
什么事？
Well, the stock market just took a huge plunge and we've lost a lot of money.
嗯，股市刚刚暴跌，我们亏损了很多钱。
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
What happened?
发生了什么？
There are many factors that weigh in, but Nasdaq is down 200 points.
有很多因素在起作用，但纳斯达克指数下跌了200点。
The Dow Jones indicator also suffered.
道琼斯指数也受到了影响。
Our portfolio is worth half of what it was worth one week ago.
我们的投资组合价值只有一周前的一半。
How is this possible?
这怎么可能？
You are supposed to be talking to our stockbrokers and making sure that our securities and investments
你应该和我们的股票经纪人沟通，确保我们的证券和投资
are safe and making a profitable return.
安全，并能获得盈利回报。
I know, sir.
我知道，先生。
We didn't expect a bull market to become a bear market all of a sudden.
我们没预料到牛市会突然变成熊市。
On the other hand, you still have some high yield trash bonds and government bonds that
另一方面，你还有一些高收益垃圾债券和政府债券，
will give us enough liquidity to cut our losses and reinvest in emerging markets.
它们能给我们足够的流动性来止损，并重新投资于新兴市场。
We could potentially make this tragedy work for us and make us think outside the box.
我们有可能让这场悲剧为我们所用，并促使我们跳出框框思考。
Do what you have to do.
做你该做的事。
One other thing.
还有一件事。
Don't tell the rest of the stockholders about this.
别告诉其他股东这件事。
If they find out it's the end of this company.
如果他们发现了，这家公司就完了。
So I remember being a little kid and watching TV with my parents and on the news there was
我记得小时候和父母一起看电视，新闻里
always the business segment and in this you'd always hear the Nasdaq is down 10 points.
总有商业板块，你总会听到纳斯达克指数下跌10点。
The Dow Jones Industrial today is down 10 points.
今天道琼斯工业指数下跌10点。
Yesterday was up two.
昨天上涨了2点。
That's an average of H. Okay.
那是一个平均值。好的。
Yeah, it's very complicated, especially if you take a look also in the newspaper.
是的，非常复杂，尤其是如果你再看一下报纸。
Sometimes it shows you different publicly traded companies and it has a bunch of numbers.
有时它会显示不同的上市公司，还有一堆数字。
It's a very interesting topic.
这是一个非常有趣的话题。
It's almost a science, I think.
我觉得它几乎是一门科学。
Very much a science and some people have made a lot of money playing the stock market and
非常像一门科学，有些人通过炒股赚了很多钱，而
trying to buy stocks when they're low, wait until they're high, sell them off and make
试图在低价时买入股票，等到高价时再抛售，大赚一笔。
tons.
大赚一笔。
Yeah, it's pretty much analyzing risk.
是啊，这基本上就是在分析风险。
So making calculated decisions and that's why they use all these formulas and all these
所以要做有计算依据的决策，这就是为什么他们要用各种公式和
different ratios and ways to ponder how much they should invest or what would they gain.
不同的比率和方法来权衡该投资多少，或者能获得什么收益。
So it's very, very interesting.
所以这非常非常有趣。
Many people compare it to gambling, but it's kind of like gambling but not really because
很多人把它比作赌博，但它有点像赌博又不完全是，因为
you don't really depend on luck.
你并不真的依赖运气。
You kind of make calculated decisions.
你是在做有计算依据的决策。
And sometimes you're trading for big, big companies or even parts of big markets like
而且有时候你交易的是大公司，甚至是整个大市场的一部分，比如
parts of entire countries.
整个国家的一部分。
A lot of people, for example, stockbrokers will invest a group of workers' retirement
很多人，比如股票经纪人，会投资一群工人的退休
funds.
基金。
They will take those funds and be like, hey, you're maybe getting 5% from the bank for
他们会拿着这些基金说，嘿，你把钱存银行可能只拿到5%的利息。
keeping your money there.
把钱给我，我给你的投资带来25%的回报。
Give me the money and I'll give you 25% yield on your investment.
所以显然他们不仅是在拿自己的声誉冒险，也是在拿别人的
And so obviously they're playing not only their reputation but also with other people's
毕生积蓄冒险。
life savings.
这就是为什么两年前泡沫在很多领域（比如房地产）破裂时，
And that's why a lot of people lost money when two years ago the bubble really burst
很多人亏了钱。
in a lot of areas like real estate.
Stock prices went down.
股票价格下跌了。
The United States went into a recession.
美国陷入了经济衰退。
And all these people's retirement funds, their savings, they lost it.
所有这些人的退休基金、他们的积蓄，都赔光了。
So you got to be careful with this kind of stuff and do your homework.
所以你得小心这类事情，做好功课。
But that's about it for us today.
但我们今天就到这里了。
Hope that you've enjoyed this lesson.
希望你喜欢这节课。
If you have questions or comments, please do visit us on our website EnglishPod.com.
如果你有问题或评论，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好了。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye.
再见。
?? 1??